Hello everyone and welcome back to
EnglishPod. We have an advanced lesson
for you today. My name
is Marco. And my name is
Katherine and I'm very
excited about this lesson Marco.
It's very interesting. It's
about a very controversial
topic and a very popular person in history,
Charles Darwin. That's right. So he's
most famous perhaps for his book The
Origin of the Species and we're going to
be talking a lot about science today.
So put your thinking caps on. Alright.
So without further ado, why don't we
listen to this dialogue for the first time.
Man, it's been forever. What have you
been up to lately? I've been busy preparing
for my exams. Not to mention all the
term papers have had to write. Same here.
I'm up to my neck and work but at
least you've got some of our holidays after
finals. Where are you headed now?
I'm going to my anthro class. We've been
focusing on Darwin all term since
it's the 200th anniversary of his birth or
whatever. I'm sick and tired of Darwin
Darwin Darwin. What? Why? How can you not
like Darwin? His work turned thousands
of years of ideas about creation on
their head. His theory of evolution
revolutionized the field of biology and
anthropology. I don't like him.
His theory of human evolution and natural
selection is full of holes. It's not
as solid as you make it out to be.
Say that again and you'll make enemies with
half of the academy. Not to mention your
professors. Furthermore, the explanation
proposed by Darwin about the origin of
the species and the process of
natural selection constitutes a grand step
towards a coherent understanding
of the world and its very beginnings.
I'm not minimizing his huge contributions
to science. It's just that his theory
reminds me of the conundrum of the chicken
and the egg. What are you talking about?
Which came first? The chicken or the
egg? This is a classic logical problem.
And I think it applies to Darwin's
theory. How did the very first living
organism come to be? Interesting. I
think that question is better suited for my
philosophy class. In the meantime,
how about we settle this with a jewel?
Interesting. They have very different
views on Charles Darwin, right? They do.
And they're both pretty nerdy people.
This is a very nerdy university like
conversation that's happening between
classes. I think maybe they're like PhD
candidates or something. All right. So
before we get to talking about some of the
ideas in today's dialogue, let's talk
about some of the words and phrases that
we hear to understand better what's
going on. The first part we're going to
talk about in today's language
takeaway. Language takeaway. All right.
On language takeaway today, let's take
a look at the first word and well, one of
the things that many people say is that
Darwin revolutionized the fields of biology.
And so he revolutionized these
because he pushed them forward.
He made many changes. He forced changes.
So people had to change the way that they
thought about these things. If you
revolutionize something a topic or an idea,
you are creating new knowledge almost,
right? Exactly. You can think of the
word revolution, which is a thing. So
you think of the Russian revolution or the
American revolution. These are times
of change. So to revolutionize is to
bring about change. Very good. All right.
So moving forward, they were talking
about human evolution, human evolution.
What is that exactly? Good question.
So you're not a monkey. I'm not a
monkey, but we come from monkeys, right?
So we evolved, right? So the process is
called human evolution. That means the
process by which humans changed
forms to become what we are today. Okay.
So you evolve. Now is it evolution
usually think of something positive, right?
Something evolves into something better.
Is it always that way? No, we have
another word for the negative, right?
So the positive is to evolve to become
better, to get worse is to devolve. Okay.
Yeah, to devolve, to go back and to
kind of lose things that you had. Okay.
Interesting. And then they were also
talking about Darwin's theory of
natural selection, natural selection. Okay.
This is maybe one of the things
that Darwin was most famous for.
And that's why we've included it in
this language takeaway because it's a key
phrase. It's something you hear
people talk about along. Okay. So natural
selection is a process again. And it's
the process by which stronger animals
survive over time and weaker animals don't.
So if there's a weak species, it
can't really survive because it keeps
dying and dying. And then finally,
there's no more. And so this is called
natural selection because no one's
actually choosing what animals will
survive, but it's kind of a natural process.
Right. Mother nature is
choosing it. Right. Very good.
So natural selection. This is one of the
things that Darwin is most famous for.
And well, as Catherine mentioned, Darwin
wrote the book Origin of the Species.
Right. So origin means beginning.
So the origin of mankind. Right.
So there are many different kinds of
animals. You could even see there are many
different kinds of like mammals, but there
are many different species within that.
So human beings, black bears,
koalas, chimpanzees. These are all
species. And so a
species is a classification.
So the origin of the species is
kind of a way of telling the story
of how all these things came about.
All right. The origin of the species.
And the last one, this word is kind of
strange. He talked about the
conundrum of the chicken and the egg.
Okay, conundrum. I love this word. It's
very funny sounding conundrum. It means
like a problem or a little or something
that's hard to understand. All right.
So in this case, it's the conundrum
of the chicken and the egg, right?
Which came first? How else can you use
conundrum? You could say that maybe there's a
situation that's very strange and
hard to understand this. This is quite a
quite a conundrum. This is quite a
conundrum we have. Yes. So it sounds very
fancy, very well educated. It does.
All right. So interesting words on language
takeaway. Why don't we move on now
to four phrases on fluency builder? Fluency
builder. All right. On fluency builder
today, we have four phrases as we said. So
what's the first one? The first
one is great. It's, it's very visual.
You say, I'm up to my neck in work. I'm up
to my neck in papers to write. All right.
So this means I have so much stuff to
do that you could pile it up and it would
come up to my neck. So I have as many
papers that are almost as tall as I am.
Exactly. And so I could say I'm up to my
neck in work. I have no more time to do
anything. Sometimes people also
say I'm up to here, and then those like,
though, though, the point, the point at
their forehead or somewhere around their
head, I'm up to, I'm up to here with
your nonsense. Exactly. So this is a way of
saying that I'm really busy, really
busy and really tired of it. All right.
And our next phrase is one that most
mothers use. I'm sick and tired. I'm sick
and tired of all of your whining. Don't
do the dishes and don't complain. Right.
So it's always, it always goes together.
You are sick and tired. Right. And sick
comes first. So I'm sick and tired of this.
I'm sick and tired of your bad attitude.
Okay. So and that means
that you are, I'm just tired
of it. I don't want you to
have a bad attitude anymore.
Or I'm just, yeah, I'm really
annoyed by it. I'm annoyed.
Okay. Sick and tired. And then we saw
a phrase that was a little bit separated.
They said the sentence went like this,
his work turned thousands of years of
ideas about creation on their head.
So to turn something on its head.
Like you said, Marco, it's split into two
parts. So he turned the field of computer
science on its head. So to turn on its head
means to completely reverse something,
to turn it around. You think 180 degrees.
Okay. And so if biology used to be one
way, then Darwin made it completely
different. So we can say that Isaac Newton
completely turned physics on its head
with his theory or his findings on gravity.
And then years and years later, we had
Albert Einstein who turned those theories
or who turned that theory on its head with
his own ideas about physics. Very good.
So to turn something on its head to
completely change the course of or prove
something to be maybe wrong. And
the last phrase that we have is the person
argued that Darwin's theories were full
of holes. Okay. So to say a theory is full
of holes is a little bit different than
saying that his pants are full of holes
because when you say something is full
of holes, maybe they actually have holes,
but a theory is it's an idea. So it can't
have holes. What you're saying is that
it's not completely sound. It's not
without some problems. And so maybe
you're saying that, well, the cookies
are gone out of the kitchen Marco.
And I saw you in the kitchen. So clearly
you ate the cookies. Right. So I can say
that's full of holes because it was me
and it was three other people who are in
the kitchen. So the other two people.
Right. So if something is full of holes
is that it has maybe mistakes or it's
still missing complete evidence to prove
it right. Or it has bad logic.
Bad logic. All right. Interesting.
So we've taken a look at
a lot of words and different
phrases here. Let's listen to
this argument one last time.
Man, it's been forever. What have
you been up to lately? I've been busy
preparing for my exams, not to
mention all the term papers have had to
write same here. I'm up to my neck
and work, but at least you've got some
or holidays after finals. Where are you
headed now? I'm going to my anthro class.
We've been focusing on
Darwin all term since it's a 200th
anniversary of his birth or whatever. I'm
sick and tired of Darwin Darwin Darwin.
What? Why? How can you
not like Darwin? His work turned
thousands of years of ideas about
creation on their head. His theory of
evolution revolutionized the
fields of biology and anthropology.
I don't like him. His theory of human
evolution and natural selection is full of
holes. It's not as solid as you make
it out to be. Save that again and you'll
make enemies with half of the academy, not
to mention your professors. Furthermore,
the explanation proposed by Darwin
about the origin of the species and the
process of natural selection constitutes
a grand step towards a coherent
understanding of the world and its
very beginnings. I'm not minimizing his
huge contributions to science.
It's just that his theory reminds me of the
conundrum of the chicken and the egg. What
are you talking about? Which came first?
The chicken or the egg? This is a
classic logical problem and I think it
applies to Darwin's theory. How did
the very first living organism come to be?
Interesting. I think that question is
better suited for my velocity class.
In the meantime, how about
we settle this with a jewel?
All right, we're back. So interesting
this Darwin's theories and his
explanations for the origin of species
and life as we know it. But there is the
opposite to this, right? There is
a certain thing called creationism.
There is and this is a big source of
controversy, especially in the United States
because in some places people
want to teach creationism as well as
evolution in schools and so this is
the big question. Are they still equal as
theories or is one theory more proven
than the other? Right. And it is kind of
hard to determine which one is better
because one is based on faith. The other
one is based more on scientific
evidence, right? So they're not really even
in the same scale as we learned before.
That's kind of like apples and oranges,
right? It is. And there are some people
who would say that we have lots of
ways of, quote unquote, proving what
happened in the past. But as long as we
weren't there, we never really do know.
Right. And there's always changes in
science. So how can we be sure that
what we know now isn't false? It isn't
misunderstanding. Right. I think for
now, this is the best explanation. But that
doesn't mean that it's the it's the
correct one. Maybe in a hundred years from
now we'll have another explanation
that's much better or maybe complementary
to this one. Well, we want to know
what you guys think come to our website
EnglishPod.com. We really want to hear
your opinions. What do you think about
this topic? It is a
little bit controversial.
So we really look
forward to your
comments and any other questions
you may have. Yep. And just a reference,
creationism is the idea that God created
the world or a superior being created
the world and that everything came
from that. And so let us know what you
think I am very curious to.
And that's about it for today. All right.
I'll see you guys there. Bye bye.